# **FELIPE ALVAREZ**

Santiago, Chile • +56951413166 • fe.alvarezdiaz@gmail.com • linkedin

#### **SUMMARY**

Data Science Specialist with experience in engineering and sports analysis. Deep knowledge in creating predictive models and performance analysis that have driven strategic decisions and process optimization in the mining industry and the sports sector. Underground mining lecturer with advanced skills in modeling tools and data analyst who has improved tactical performance in professional handball. My portfolio highlights innovative projects that demonstrate my ability to transform complex data into concrete and strategic solutions

#### **SKILLS**

- Python
- Django
- Machine learning
- SQL

- Git
- Power BI
- Computer vision
- PyTorch

- TensorFlow
- AWS
- GPC
- Softs Skills
- Spanish Native
- English B2 C1
- France A2 B1

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Data Science, Paris, Francia

## Analyst for Joinville Le Pont Handball Team

Sept 2022 – May 2023

- Execution of a descriptive analysis and data visualization, identification of weak points, segmentation of players, and development of predictive modeling to optimize game tactics.
- With this, technical and tactical decisions were made, which reflected a significant improvement in the trend of results, helping to avoid relegation.

# Underground Mining Professor, Curico, Chile

Sept 2021 – Dec 2021

### **Creative Director**

• Data analysis of boreholes to perform geological modeling with the aim of determining an appropriate extraction method and designing it, using the Minesight mining software

## **PORTFOLIO**

#### Prediction of Potential Customers to Leave a Bank

Product Manager (Nov 2011 – Dec 2014)

- Development of a model to predict which bank customers might leave in the future, identifying the determining variables in the customer's decision.
- Technologies used: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, sklearn.

## Sports Analysis: Performance Evaluation of a Handball Goalkeeper

- Comprehensive analysis of the shots received by the goalkeeper during the season, identifying trends and weak points to optimize his performance.
- Technologies used: Excel and Power Bi.

### Computer Vision Model for Goal Detection in Handball Matches

- Development and optimization of a computer vision model for automatic goal detection in handball matches, significantly enhancing sports analysis efficiency.
- Technologies used: YOLOv8, DeepSORT, FastAPI, Streamlit

### **EDUCATION**

Data Science Bootcamp, Le Wagon

Jan 2024 – Mar 2024

Mining Engineer, University of Talca, Chile

Mar 2013 – Jan 2019